Guide to the George Ephraim Sokolsky Manuscripts
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
George Ephraim Sokolsky Manuscripts,
1919-1962
Sokolsky, George E. (George Ephraim), 1893-1962.
ca. 9,500 items (23 boxes, 10 v., 28 large envelopes, 1,800 phonodiscs)
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY.
4079353
Biographical Note
Columnist, author, lecturer.
Scope and Content
Manuscripts of Sokolsky, including notes and typescripts for his newspaper columns, magazine articles, radio broadcasts, and for several of his books, including Outlines of Universal History, Tinder Box of Asia, and We Jews. Also, scrapbooks and envelopes of clippings of his newspaper columns and articles; and approximately 1,800 transcriptions of Sokolsky's radio broadcasts.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into 2 series:
Series I: Manuscripts
Series II: Clippings
Subjects
Radio programs.; Newspapers--Sections, columns, etc.; Journalism.; Scrapbooks.; Sound recordings.; Authors.; Journalists.; Lecturers.
Access Restrictions
The following boxes are located off-site: 2-22. You will need to request this material from the Rare Book and Manuscript Library at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
This collection has no restrictions.
Acquisition
1962 M-62 Estate of George E. Sokolsky Gift
- Series I: Manuscripts
  - Outlines of Universal History (Box 1)
  - Tinder Box of Asia (Box 2)
  - Handbook for Ambitious Girls (Box 3)
  - Liberty Articles (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous articles (Box 6-9)
  - Broadcasts (Box 10-14)
  - Radio Broadcasts, 1948-1961 [mimeographs] (Box 14A & 14B)
  - Unused and incomplete manuscripts (Box 15)
- Series II: Clippings
  - Clippings (Box 16)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1919-1923, (1 scrapbook #1)
    [Missing August 2004]
  - Newspaper clippings, 1923-1925, (1 scrapbook #2) (Box 17)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1925-1927, (1 scrapbook #3) (Box 17)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1925-1928, (1 scrapbook #4) (Box 18)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1928/1929, (1 scrapbook #5) (Box 18)
  - New York Times & Other Articles, 1928-1938, (1 scrapbook #6) (Box 617)
  - New York Herald Tribune Articles, 1936-1940, (1 scrapbook #7) (Box 617)
  - Liberty Magazine Articles, 1939-1942, (1 scrapbook #8) (Box 618)
  - New York Sun Articles, 15 July 1940 - 21 Feb. 1942, (1 scrapbook #9) (Box 618)
  - New York Sun Articles, 23 Feb. 1942 - 31 March 1943, (1 scrapbook #10) (Box 619)
  - New York Sun Articles, 1 April 1943 - 3 June 1944, (1 scrapbook #11) (Box 619)
  - New York Sun Articles, 5 June 1944 - 30 June 1945, (1 scrapbook #12) (Box 620)
  - New York Sun Articles, July 1945 - December 1945, (1 scrapbook #13) (Box 620)
  - New York Sun Articles, Jan. 1946 - Dec. 1946, (1 scrapbook #14) (Box 620)
  - New York Mirror Editorials, Jan. 1946 - Dec. 1947, (1 scrapbook #15) (Box 621)
  - New York Sun Articles, Jan. 1947 - Dec. 1947, (1 scrapbook #16) (Box 621)
  - New York Sun Articles, Jan. 1948 - Dec. 1948, (1 scrapbook #17) (Box 621)
  - New York Mirror Editorials, Jan. 1948 - Dec. 1949, (1 scrapbook #18) (Box 622)
  - New York Sun Articles, Jan. 1949 - Jan. 1950, (1 scrapbook #19) (Box 622)
  - New York Mirror Editorials, Jan. 1950 - Dec. 1951, (1 scrapbook #20) (Box 622)
  - King Features Articles, Jan. 1950 - Dec. 1950, (1 scrapbook #21) (Box 623)
  - King Features Articles, Jan. 1951 - Dec. 1951, (1 scrapbook #22) (Box 623)
  - King Features Articles, Jan. 1952 - Dec. 1952, (1 scrapbook #23) (Box 623)
  - New York Mirror Editorials, Jan. 1952 - Dec. 1953, (1 scrapbook #24) (Box 624)
  - King Features Articles, Jan. 1953 - Dec. 1953S, (1 scrapbook #25) (Box 624)
  - King Features Articles, Jan. 1954 - Dec. 1954, (1 scrapbook #26) (Box 624)
  - New York Mirror Editorials, Jan. 1954 - Dec. 1954, (1 scrapbook #27) (Box 625)
  - King Featrures Articles, Jan. 1955 - Dec. 1955, (1 scrapbook #28) (Box 625)
  - King Featrures Articles, Jan. 1956 - Dec. 1956, (1 scrapbook #29) (Box 625)
  - New York Mirror Editorials, Jan. 1956 - Dec. 1957, (1 scrapbook #30) (Box 626)
  - King Features Articles, Jan. 1857 - Dec. 1957, (1 scrapbook #31) (Box 626)
  - King Features Articles, Jan. 1958 - Dec. 1958, (1 scrapbook #32) (Box 626)
  - New York Mirror Editorials, Jan. 1958 - Dec. 1959, (1 scrapbook #33) (Box 627)
  - King Features Articles, Jan. 1959 - Dec. 1959, (1 scrapbook #34) (Box 627)
  - King Features Articles, Jan. 1960 - Dec. 1960, (1 scrapbook #35) (Box 627)
  - New York Mirror Editorials, Jan. 1960 - Dec. 1960, (1 scrapbook #36) (Box 628)
  - King Featrures Articles, Jan. 1961 - Dec. 1961, (1 scrapbook #37) (Box 628)
  - New York Mirror Editorials, Jan. 1961 - Dec. 1961, (1 scrapbook #38) (Box 628)
  - King Features Articles, 1962, (1 scrapbook #39) (Box 628)
  - Miscellaneous Articles and Speeches, (1 scrapbook #40) (Box Box 19)
  - Miscellaneous Articles and Speeches, (1 scrapbook #41) (Box Box 19)
  - Miscellaneous Articles and Speeches, (1 scrapbook #42) (Box Box 20)
  - Miscellaneous Scrapbooks, (1 scrapbook #43) (Box Box 20)
  - Atlantic Monthly Scrapbook, (1 scrapbook #44) (Box Box 21)
  - Christmas Cards Scrapbook, (1 scrapbook #45) (Box Box 21)
  - National Association of Manufactures, Broadcasts 1-50, (1 scrapbook #46) (Box Box 21)
  - National Association of Manufactures, Broadcasts 51-100, (1 scrapbook #47) (Box Box 22)
  - National Association of Manufactures, Broadcasts 101-150, (1 scrapbook #48) (Box Box 22)
  - National Association of Manufactures, Broadcasts 151-172, (1 scrapbook #49) (Box Box 22)